<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reflection on Joshua Mauldin</title>
    <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/tags/Reflection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reflection on Joshua Mauldin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://joshuamauldin.com/tags/Reflection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What I learned making my first VR app (Prototypr)</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00028/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00028/</guid>
      <description>Original post
Virtual Reality Experience by Mooms from the Noun Project
I recently made my first VR app for a client who commissioned an app to celebrate their 100th anniversary. In it, you walk through a 3D art gallery complete with with audio and imagery to understand their history.
Having primarily designed for mobile over the last few years, this was a fun new medium to explore. The new constraints and considerations were interesting, too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Requiem for a side project, quitting AwesomeGIFs</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00023/</guid>
      <description>Original post
A feeling came over me in 2009 when GeoCities was shutting down: ‘I don’t want all those GIFs to somehow disappear! They’re magic.’ So I made a home for them, and in the span of a few short weeks, AwesomeGIFs was born.
Powered by the humble WordPress, it operated like so many blogs of its time, publishing new GIFs each day. I loved those misfit GIFs so much — they turned out to be so much more fun than I’d ever imagine, and it warmed me to see so many people take to them like they did.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In which a nerd changes almost every part of his life to be better designer</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00015/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00015/</guid>
      <description>Original post
💡 I wrote this article in 2014, and my views have evolved since this. Focus is still important, but please do not change every part of your life to be a better designer. Instead, change it to be a more thoughtful and kind human. The design, or whatever you do, will naturally follow. A guide for designers young (and not so young) # As a young designer, I found myself unable to focus on my work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
