<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Focus on Joshua Mauldin</title>
    <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/tags/Focus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Focus on Joshua Mauldin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://joshuamauldin.com/tags/Focus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>End of Day ceremonies, the key to sleeping better and staying focused during quarantine</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00006/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00006/</guid>
      <description>Original post
Remember the last time you couldn’t get something out of your head and you woke up thinking about it in the middle of the night? The last few weeks of quarantine have been one continuous stretch of undifferentiated time and it’s become hard to turn things off. So I’ll share what I did about it in hopes of it helping you too. After putting this self-care routine into practice, I’ve been much more effective and focused during the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I turned off my push notifications and I’ve never been happier</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00014/</guid>
      <description>Original post
Over the holiday, I did the unthinkable: turned off push notifications from Messages. Up to that point, I’d received a steadily-increasing stream of messages from co-workers and friends—my head was buzzing as much as my phone. It was hard to get any quiet time in my own head and I was tired of my tiny illuminated rectangle commanding my attention.
When I put a stop to it, I became more at peace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notifications stress me out. How I cut them down to improve my well-being (CBC Radio)</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00019/</guid>
      <description>Original post
(Jason Vermes)
I&amp;rsquo;m really fed up with notifications.
When it&amp;rsquo;s not the group chat blowing up, it&amp;rsquo;s a breaking news alert. When it&amp;rsquo;s not a reminder to meet your step goal, your budget app is letting you know you&amp;rsquo;ve spent too much at Starbucks this week.
Now, before you say anything, I know. I can just turn them off.
But I want certain notifications to get through. Texts from my Mom, for example.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
