<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Log on Joshua Graves</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/log/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Log on Joshua Graves</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>2024, Joshua Graves</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/log/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Beginnings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/log/2025-01-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/log/2025-01-20/</guid>
      <description>I spent the last year living in Joshua Tree, CA. It was wonderful. The landscape is incredible, the energy invigorating. But now I’m splitting my time between there and somewhere else. So it’s as if I have two homes now.&#xA;Dahlia I adopted a perfect little tuxedo cat who is so very sweet to me. I had heart eyes when I held her for the first time. It’s been over a year since I’ve had pets in my life, and I’m so happy they’re back.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feeding your demons</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/log/2023-12-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/log/2023-12-12/</guid>
      <description>I’ve long wondered if fighting off your demons, waging battle after battle against your problems, is the best approach. It’s energy intensive and often feels like you’re fighting the tide.&#xA;As someone with complex post traumatic stress disorder, I felt exhaustion in the marrow of my bones after wading into some of these battles. Maybe I beat back something or achieved some small victory, but it felt like a losing proposition that came at great cost.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wax stamps</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/log/2023-11-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/log/2023-11-30/</guid>
      <description>Used a wax stamp for the first time to address thank-you cards. It was beautiful and meditative to slowly watch this rich, luciously colored wax melt and drip, drop by drop, onto some thick and sturdy paper. Maybe I should make my own.&#xA;Other things of interest are insight systems. Anything related to tangential thinking and how it lead to deep insights fascinates me. So far, it&amp;rsquo;s looking into astrology, tarot, and bone reading.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Limpiar Sus Huesos</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/log/2023-11-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/log/2023-11-13/</guid>
      <description>I posted a couple new pieces of art, one inspired by Oppenheimer and the other by old horror films.&#xA;Paid a visit to Hollywood Forever to experience Dia De Los Muertos. Overwhelmed with the beauty and respect for people&amp;rsquo;s loved ones. Especially so by the altars dedicated to pets. See more photos here.&#xA;On that same weekend, I met someone from Oaxaca who told me she and her town grew up doing something called &amp;ldquo;limpiar sus huesos.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silver Nitrate, Design as an Attitude</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/log/2023-10-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/log/2023-10-18/</guid>
      <description>It was a good weekend for movies. TMNT was so good, like it had no business being so good. I have seen way too many &amp;ldquo;revivals&amp;rdquo; of nostalgic shows that were boring or lifeless and this wasn&amp;rsquo;t one of them.&#xA;In the same weekend I also saw Talk to Me. Horror movie of the year, hands down. What a great, tight story that was. Excited to see the prequel they shot in secret.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s get spooky!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/log/2023-10-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/log/2023-10-04/</guid>
      <description>My favorite time of year is here. Hooray for spooky season! I updated the site with spooky Halloween colors, too.&#xA;Red mode on iPhone # I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to make reading on my phone as easy as I can, and I remember working in the darkroom a lot in college. It was easy to see in there with a red light and didn&amp;rsquo;t hurt my eyes. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d see if iOS had the ability to do this, given that it lets you go greyscale and filters other colors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I redid my site</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/log/2023-09-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/log/2023-09-26/</guid>
      <description>I had a few reasons for redoing my site. Turns out said reasons fold up nicely inside the concept of something called web sustainability. I learned about this after seeing a W3C&amp;rsquo;s working group publish a sustainability guidelines report in September of 2023. It resonates deeply and is worth a read.&#xA;One wild stat they shared was that if the Internet were a country, it would be the world&amp;rsquo;s fourth largest polluter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reorganization and ePubs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/log/2023-09-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/log/2023-09-15/</guid>
      <description>Did some reorganization to take advantage of Hugo&amp;rsquo;s page bundles, which will make updates a little smoother and keep the site tidy.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;d wanted a workflow where I could easily copy/paste from my writing environment directly into Hugo but that proved a little too tricky to set up.&#xA;ePubs # Turns out, you can make ebooks out of markdown sites. So I turned The Nevermore into an ePub book! It took a lot of work to get how I wanted, but it&amp;rsquo;s easy enough to do with Pandoc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Nevermore and wget</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/log/2023-09-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/log/2023-09-12/</guid>
      <description>We had a friend over for an introvert art night, basically we whittled time away working on art projects individually. I&amp;rsquo;d long been considering which collection of Poe&amp;rsquo;s work I should get, but the editions I&amp;rsquo;ve seen are shiny and have terrible line length and typesetting. Yes, I am that kind of person. What good is a book if it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to read?&#xA;So, having no desire to do physical art, I turned to the world of static site generators.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sculpture and LACMA</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/log/2023-09-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/log/2023-09-05/</guid>
      <description>Art # Started in on a clay sculpture. I was inspired by Foundation’s incredible opening credits, and thought it would be fun to sculpt a half human/half bone…thing. So I got some polymer clay, primer, and set to work.&#xA;Initially I wanted to have it entirely emblazoned with glitter but it really hid the subtle textures I put on the face. So I got some adhesive I could paint on and then applied the glitter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Markdown to Word Doc, Writing, Notes on Complexity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/log/2023-09-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/log/2023-09-04/</guid>
      <description>Writing # I’m considering what to do once We Need To Talk is done. I’ll still promote and coach, but what else? Considering:&#xA;Writing a couple more horror stories Working on a sculpture project with resin (and skulls, probably) Relaxing and doing nothing, which I seem incapable of doing While in the course of doing some research, I came to a realization about oneself: if another person demands a change to your life or self in order to gain their acceptance, they have already decided to not accept you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Astrolabes, iMac G4s</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/log/2023-09-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/log/2023-09-01/</guid>
      <description>Really interested in this doc I saw on how we measure time. Astrolabes are beautiful pieces work. Why don&amp;rsquo;t we make things that beautiful anymore? Everyone&amp;rsquo;s obsessed with rectangles and silly minimalism, we could be obsessed over beautifully crafted things.&#xA;The Blackening earned a place in my favorite horror comedy movies. It was a delight watching the plot unfold. It was a little like Clue and Bodies Bodies Bodies, but still unique enough to stand on its own.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personal LLM explorations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/log/2023-08-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/log/2023-08-21/</guid>
      <description>Tech # Lots more fun to be had on the LLM front.&#xA;Tavily might be helpful in other research. It&amp;rsquo;s really my ideal use case for such a technology. In a similar vein, GPT Researcher seems like it might also fit the bill for unbiased (I hope) research.&#xA;Quivr seems interesting, too, as it&amp;rsquo;s promising to be a second brain. If it&amp;rsquo;s more useful than Spotlight, I&amp;rsquo;ll be interested.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plato&#39;s Cave, Norma Design</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/log/2023-08-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/log/2023-08-18/</guid>
      <description>Tech # Abandoned the search engine project. It was too difficult to diagnose issues with the experience I had. Also the instructions had a lot of assumed knowledge but that’s not impossible to address.&#xA;Reading # Finished Salem’s Lot, and liked it. Most of the book was chatter about small town goings-on and a slow starter. King’s prose is still wonderful, and I highlighted so many beautiful sentences. The book seemed to have some inconsistencies with how vampires worked in the world (they were padlocked inside their resting places?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tech reviews for my book, horror writing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/log/2023-08-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/log/2023-08-02/</guid>
      <description>Survived my first round of tech review for We Need to Talk. It was a cognitive powerlift to work through all of it. But the book is better for said feedback, which I received with joy. Just a few more, then final edits.&#xA;I joined the horror writer association. I have intentions on more fiction writing. We’ll see about doing more once I get through book edits for WNTT.&#xA;Feeling confident in my decision to focus on the digital garden, it’s fun to just…put stuff out there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python, LLMs, and new gigs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/log/2023-08-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/log/2023-08-01/</guid>
      <description>Recently started a contract gig, aimed at helping the prison system in California. It’s a slow start and unlike any other job I’ve taken on.&#xA;There wasn’t a big, or any, welcome. At first it was depressing but now it feels right. Past jobs have been a little too heavy on “culture” and for someone who is recovering from being in shitty environments that at first seemed great, I welcome it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My intention for this new site</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/log/2023-07-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/log/2023-07-31/</guid>
      <description>I intend to keep this wiki going for at least five years. Longer if it’s fruitful for me, but I don’t want to be chained to this forever.&#xA;Intentions are everything to me, as success usually doesn’t come without them.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
