<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Advice on The Garden</title>
    <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/tags/Advice/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Advice on The Garden</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://joshuamauldin.com/tags/Advice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What we look for in a product designer’s portfolio</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/guides/published-00029/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/guides/published-00029/</guid>
      <description>Original post
I had a lot of good responses to a question I put out on LinkedIn about advice for product design portfolios so I thought I’d expound on that here in hopes of helping you get called in for an interview.
While the principles here are applicable to almost all types of design roles, I’m going to narrow the focus of this to folks who are seeking a product design role.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Work, Quarantine Edition</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/guides/published-00004/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/guides/published-00004/</guid>
      <description>Something I deeply believe is that if you’re able to have focused time to work, you’re going to be able to go further, faster, and deeper than those who don’t.
That’s been especially true for me in this time of quarantine. When this began, I was hyper-available to people, answering emails and chats much quicker than I would usually. That, paired with the uncertainty of this pandemic made for a huge drag on my focus and craft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective Animation</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/guides/published-00005/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/guides/published-00005/</guid>
      <description>Original post
Over the years, animation evolved from a nice-to-have concept to a core feature. Now, the best companies use animation to inform, delight, and reward the people using their products. Let’s talk about how animation helps and how to use it in our work.
Animation Provides Guidance # I think a lot about this quote from Steve Krug in Don’t Make Me Think:
“We don’t read pages. We scan them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prototyping iOS And Android Apps With Sketch (Smashing Magazine)</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/guides/published-00021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/guides/published-00021/</guid>
      <description>Original post
After the untimely (and still kind of sad) demise of Fireworks, I found myself looking for other ways to design apps and websites. I also had the desire to produce something more interactive for when I talk about my work with stakeholders. It turned out that Sketch, when paired with some other neat tools, would be a big part of this workflow.
In this article, I’ll talk you through why you should prototype and how you can do it with Sketch and prototyping tools such as Flinto and InVision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In which a nerd changes almost every part of his life to be better designer</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/guides/published-00015/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/guides/published-00015/</guid>
      <description>Original post
💡 I wrote this article in 2014, and my views have evolved since this. Focus is still important, but please do not change every part of your life to be a better designer. Instead, change it to be a more thoughtful and kind human. The design, or whatever you do, will naturally follow. A guide for designers young (and not so young) # As a young designer, I found myself unable to focus on my work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
