<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Collaboration on Joshua Mauldin</title>
    <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/tags/Collaboration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Collaboration on Joshua Mauldin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://joshuamauldin.com/tags/Collaboration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How To Give Effective Feedback Remotely (Smashing Magazine)</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/guides/published-00007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/guides/published-00007/</guid>
      <description>Original post
We need more good feedback in our world, and I don’t just mean the type of feedback that celebrates your good work. I’m talking about feedback that is actionable, specific, and kind; feedback that does not set us on edge or make us fall into an anxious spiral; feedback that helps us collaborate more effectively. The kind of feedback that is actually really hard to do when working remotely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How using Cranky Conclusions makes tough conversations easier</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/guides/published-00012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/guides/published-00012/</guid>
      <description>Original post
Ever needed to tell a teammate something tough but fear they’ll get too defensive? Here’s one way that’s proven to work. # https://miro.medium.com/v2/resize:fit:10184/0*kOKfC0fS6aLcRDxb
Photo by Matthew Henry on Unsplash
You’re going to say the technique I’m about to share is just a glorified way of manipulating someone. Hear me out though.
Not all conflict is easy to address. We’re by no means perfect. We put so much of ourselves into our work that it’s hard to not take some feedback personally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Prime Directive and the limits of assuming positive intent</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/guides/published-00025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/guides/published-00025/</guid>
      <description>Original post
Here’s the most helpful thing I’ve ever learned by far about conflict: before you have a conversation with someone, make sure you assume positive intent. Read on to discover a technique you can use to apply that idea — if you’re like me, you’ll find it will resolve most conflict before it starts. And, in a fun plot twist, we’ll also cover how this idea shouldn’t be applied at all times because it can harm underrepresented folks if we aren’t careful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spock, Kirk, and the ideal designer/engineer relationship</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/guides/published-00024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/guides/published-00024/</guid>
      <description>Original post
Not pictured: the amazing idea Spock and Kirk come up with together.
I tend to think about Star Trek when considering how designers and engineers should work together. After all, it wouldn’t be Star Trek if you only had Kirk — you need Spock to balance him out (and it’d be kind of boring if it were just Spock, right?).
Spock and Kirk work together and solve difficult problems.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
