<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>published on Joshua Mauldin</title>
    <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/categories/published/</link>
    <description>Recent content in published on Joshua Mauldin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://joshuamauldin.com/categories/published/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How To Give Effective Feedback Remotely (Smashing Magazine)</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00007/</guid>
      <description>Original post
We need more good feedback in our world, and I don’t just mean the type of feedback that celebrates your good work. I’m talking about feedback that is actionable, specific, and kind; feedback that does not set us on edge or make us fall into an anxious spiral; feedback that helps us collaborate more effectively. The kind of feedback that is actually really hard to do when working remotely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What we look for in a product designer’s portfolio</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00029/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00029/</guid>
      <description>Original post
I had a lot of good responses to a question I put out on LinkedIn about advice for product design portfolios so I thought I’d expound on that here in hopes of helping you get called in for an interview.
While the principles here are applicable to almost all types of design roles, I’m going to narrow the focus of this to folks who are seeking a product design role.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Need a Code of Ethics.</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00027/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00027/</guid>
      <description>Original post
I keep wondering what we can do to ensure we’re building a better world with the products we make and if we need a code of ethics. So often I see people fall through the cracks because they’re “edge cases” or “not the target audience.” But at the end of the day, we’re still talking about humans.
Other professions that can deeply alter someone’s life have a code of ethics and conduct they must adhere to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>End of Day ceremonies, the key to sleeping better and staying focused during quarantine</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00006/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00006/</guid>
      <description>Original post
Remember the last time you couldn’t get something out of your head and you woke up thinking about it in the middle of the night? The last few weeks of quarantine have been one continuous stretch of undifferentiated time and it’s become hard to turn things off. So I’ll share what I did about it in hopes of it helping you too. After putting this self-care routine into practice, I’ve been much more effective and focused during the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How using Cranky Conclusions makes tough conversations easier</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00012/</guid>
      <description>Original post
Ever needed to tell a teammate something tough but fear they’ll get too defensive? Here’s one way that’s proven to work. # https://miro.medium.com/v2/resize:fit:10184/0*kOKfC0fS6aLcRDxb
Photo by Matthew Henry on Unsplash
You’re going to say the technique I’m about to share is just a glorified way of manipulating someone. Hear me out though.
Not all conflict is easy to address. We’re by no means perfect. We put so much of ourselves into our work that it’s hard to not take some feedback personally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Prime Directive and the limits of assuming positive intent</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00025/</guid>
      <description>Original post
Here’s the most helpful thing I’ve ever learned by far about conflict: before you have a conversation with someone, make sure you assume positive intent. Read on to discover a technique you can use to apply that idea — if you’re like me, you’ll find it will resolve most conflict before it starts. And, in a fun plot twist, we’ll also cover how this idea shouldn’t be applied at all times because it can harm underrepresented folks if we aren’t careful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How video games taught me to be better at conflict</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00013/</guid>
      <description>Original post
The Legend of Zelda
I played a lot of video games growing up. It all started with The Legend of Zelda. I had such bad allergies that most of my adventuring had to be more pixel-based than anything. I didn’t expect to learn all that time spent playing video games would amount to anything, especially when it came to conflict resolution. Turns out there’s a lot more in common with old school video games and modern day human behavior than you’d think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Mirror brainstorms — a product design exercise (UX Collective)</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00003/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00003/</guid>
      <description>Original post
Black Mirror on Twitter
I want to have more ethical products. I feel like we all do. Sometimes, though, we don’t consider how this amazing thing we’re working on might have some unintended and negative consequences.
In my job, I help clients build products. Part of the process is framing the project and defining our goals. We also talk about anti-goals, which are things we absolutely don’t want to happen and run counter to our intentions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned making my first VR app (Prototypr)</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00028/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00028/</guid>
      <description>Original post
Virtual Reality Experience by Mooms from the Noun Project
I recently made my first VR app for a client who commissioned an app to celebrate their 100th anniversary. In it, you walk through a 3D art gallery complete with with audio and imagery to understand their history.
Having primarily designed for mobile over the last few years, this was a fun new medium to explore. The new constraints and considerations were interesting, too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I turned off my push notifications and I’ve never been happier</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00014/</guid>
      <description>Original post
Over the holiday, I did the unthinkable: turned off push notifications from Messages. Up to that point, I’d received a steadily-increasing stream of messages from co-workers and friends—my head was buzzing as much as my phone. It was hard to get any quiet time in my own head and I was tired of my tiny illuminated rectangle commanding my attention.
When I put a stop to it, I became more at peace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notifications stress me out. How I cut them down to improve my well-being (CBC Radio)</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00019/</guid>
      <description>Original post
(Jason Vermes)
I&amp;rsquo;m really fed up with notifications.
When it&amp;rsquo;s not the group chat blowing up, it&amp;rsquo;s a breaking news alert. When it&amp;rsquo;s not a reminder to meet your step goal, your budget app is letting you know you&amp;rsquo;ve spent too much at Starbucks this week.
Now, before you say anything, I know. I can just turn them off.
But I want certain notifications to get through. Texts from my Mom, for example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective Animation</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00005/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00005/</guid>
      <description>Original post
Over the years, animation evolved from a nice-to-have concept to a core feature. Now, the best companies use animation to inform, delight, and reward the people using their products. Let’s talk about how animation helps and how to use it in our work.
Animation Provides Guidance # I think a lot about this quote from Steve Krug in Don’t Make Me Think:
“We don’t read pages. We scan them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Push Notifications, the good, the bad, and the wtf could u not (UX Collective)</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00022/</guid>
      <description>Original post
Push notifications are incredibly handy for giving you important information. Your flight being delayed? Really helpful to know. Getting a notification for everything one of the Avengers is posting about? Probably not.
Just like you’re going to ignore or shut down the person who continuously interrupts you, you’re more likely to do the same to an app that bothers you with trivial information.
Push notifications are interruptive and we must be careful in our use of them if we are to retain our customers’ happiness and trust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving Your Product A Soul (Smashing Magazine)</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00008/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00008/</guid>
      <description>Original post
After a few years of designing products for clients, I began to feel fatigued. I wondered why. Turns out, I’d been chasing metric after metric. “Increase those page views!” “Help people spend more time in the app!” And it kept coming. Still, something was missing. I knew that meeting goals was part of what a designer does, but I could see how my work could easily become commoditized and less fulfilling unless something changed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving Your Product A Soul (Smashing Magazine)</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00009/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00009/</guid>
      <description>Original post
After a few years of designing products for clients, I began to feel fatigued. I wondered why. Turns out, I’d been chasing metric after metric. “Increase those page views!” “Help people spend more time in the app!” And it kept coming. Still, something was missing. I knew that meeting goals was part of what a designer does, but I could see how my work could easily become commoditized and less fulfilling unless something changed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for perfect readability with a little help from The Big Lebowski</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00026/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00026/</guid>
      <description>Original post
I’ve had lots of conversations about typography over the last few years. Which is cool, because I love it so much (so much that I decided to make my own typeface). It’s exciting to see so many designers caring about making a beautiful group of letters that people want to read.
One common theme I see in these conversations is how to get the best readability with text. We usually end up talking about serif vs sans serif, line height, line spacing, and other tricks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I pulled a HULK SMASH on my social media presence</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00030/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00030/</guid>
      <description>Original post
I’ve had this feeling that the amount of brainspace that social media occupied was out of balance for me.
I found myself in a problematic situation more often that I’d like: checking social media during every bit of downtime, or when I was trying to solve a particularly difficult design problem. It made getting things done and being present harder than it should. I needed to be more focused.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My week with Soylent 1.4, or “Oh god I want a burger”</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00018/</guid>
      <description>Original post
💡 I wrote this article in 2015. While I like that I was curious, I want to be clear in that I absolutely do not recommend this kind of stuff. Also, it’s fun to note that everything from this era is basically a clickbait style headline. Ugh. I’m always curious about how changing a habit will affect me and have little aversion to change. My main apps for email, search, and anything else get regularly switched, and so do my mobile OSes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Requiem for a side project, quitting AwesomeGIFs</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00023/</guid>
      <description>Original post
A feeling came over me in 2009 when GeoCities was shutting down: ‘I don’t want all those GIFs to somehow disappear! They’re magic.’ So I made a home for them, and in the span of a few short weeks, AwesomeGIFs was born.
Powered by the humble WordPress, it operated like so many blogs of its time, publishing new GIFs each day. I loved those misfit GIFs so much — they turned out to be so much more fun than I’d ever imagine, and it warmed me to see so many people take to them like they did.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prototyping iOS And Android Apps With Sketch (Smashing Magazine)</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00021/</guid>
      <description>Original post
After the untimely (and still kind of sad) demise of Fireworks, I found myself looking for other ways to design apps and websites. I also had the desire to produce something more interactive for when I talk about my work with stakeholders. It turned out that Sketch, when paired with some other neat tools, would be a big part of this workflow.
In this article, I’ll talk you through why you should prototype and how you can do it with Sketch and prototyping tools such as Flinto and InVision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spock, Kirk, and the ideal designer/engineer relationship</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00024/</guid>
      <description>Original post
Not pictured: the amazing idea Spock and Kirk come up with together.
I tend to think about Star Trek when considering how designers and engineers should work together. After all, it wouldn’t be Star Trek if you only had Kirk — you need Spock to balance him out (and it’d be kind of boring if it were just Spock, right?).
Spock and Kirk work together and solve difficult problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In which a nerd changes almost every part of his life to be better designer</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00015/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00015/</guid>
      <description>Original post
💡 I wrote this article in 2014, and my views have evolved since this. Focus is still important, but please do not change every part of your life to be a better designer. Instead, change it to be a more thoughtful and kind human. The design, or whatever you do, will naturally follow. A guide for designers young (and not so young) # As a young designer, I found myself unable to focus on my work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Make An Effective Style Guide With Adobe Fireworks (Smashing Magazine)</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00011/</guid>
      <description>Original post
I started with style guides like any other obsessive-compulsive designer: with the desire to make it simple to maintain and grow a design. Plus, knowing which component to use in a given situation is nice, too, right? Since making this a regular practice, I’ve found it’s been like having a nice combination of a CSS class and a pattern library all in one.
One of the first questions, understandably, is why use Fireworks for a style guide?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iOS Grid System, A Free Extension For Adobe Fireworks (Smashing Magazine)</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00016/</guid>
      <description>Original post
About The Author # Joshua Mauldin is a design leader and visual artist who got his start creating websites for bands. Since then, he’s designed 5-star mobile apps and built … More about Joshua ↬
Email Newsletter # Your (smashing) email
Weekly tips on front-end &amp;amp; UX. Trusted by 200,000+ folks.
I’ll come right out and say it. I think the grid is the unsung hero of a good design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My real problem with in-app rating modules</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00017/</guid>
      <description>Original post
“Like this app? Give us 5 stars! UGH STOP PLZ.” # The conversation where folks are growing collectively tired of being asked to rate apps has been interesting to watch.
Some tech folks want to encourage users to rate an app 1 star because they asked for a rating. I think that’s unfair, because that doesn’t seem like a real review at all to me. It doesn’t tell me that the app is buggy, that it steals my data, or doesn’t alert me to a tornado.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How smartphones could improve texting emergency services</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00010/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00010/</guid>
      <description>Original post
As of May 24, 2014, the main 4 carriers in the US will allow texting with 911. That’s great, but I wondered what it would look like if smartphones could build on top of that idea.
I want design to do good and feel like a moment of crisis is an ideal spot to employ thoughtful design to ease a difficult situation. Plus, it’s fun to weave different technologies together.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
