<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thoughtful Design on Joshua Mauldin</title>
    <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/tags/Thoughtful-Design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thoughtful Design on Joshua Mauldin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://joshuamauldin.com/tags/Thoughtful-Design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>We Need a Code of Ethics.</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00027/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00027/</guid>
      <description>Original post
I keep wondering what we can do to ensure we’re building a better world with the products we make and if we need a code of ethics. So often I see people fall through the cracks because they’re “edge cases” or “not the target audience.” But at the end of the day, we’re still talking about humans.
Other professions that can deeply alter someone’s life have a code of ethics and conduct they must adhere to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Prime Directive and the limits of assuming positive intent</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00025/</guid>
      <description>Original post
Here’s the most helpful thing I’ve ever learned by far about conflict: before you have a conversation with someone, make sure you assume positive intent. Read on to discover a technique you can use to apply that idea — if you’re like me, you’ll find it will resolve most conflict before it starts. And, in a fun plot twist, we’ll also cover how this idea shouldn’t be applied at all times because it can harm underrepresented folks if we aren’t careful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Mirror brainstorms — a product design exercise (UX Collective)</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00003/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00003/</guid>
      <description>Original post
Black Mirror on Twitter
I want to have more ethical products. I feel like we all do. Sometimes, though, we don’t consider how this amazing thing we’re working on might have some unintended and negative consequences.
In my job, I help clients build products. Part of the process is framing the project and defining our goals. We also talk about anti-goals, which are things we absolutely don’t want to happen and run counter to our intentions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I turned off my push notifications and I’ve never been happier</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00014/</guid>
      <description>Original post
Over the holiday, I did the unthinkable: turned off push notifications from Messages. Up to that point, I’d received a steadily-increasing stream of messages from co-workers and friends—my head was buzzing as much as my phone. It was hard to get any quiet time in my own head and I was tired of my tiny illuminated rectangle commanding my attention.
When I put a stop to it, I became more at peace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notifications stress me out. How I cut them down to improve my well-being (CBC Radio)</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00019/</guid>
      <description>Original post
(Jason Vermes)
I&amp;rsquo;m really fed up with notifications.
When it&amp;rsquo;s not the group chat blowing up, it&amp;rsquo;s a breaking news alert. When it&amp;rsquo;s not a reminder to meet your step goal, your budget app is letting you know you&amp;rsquo;ve spent too much at Starbucks this week.
Now, before you say anything, I know. I can just turn them off.
But I want certain notifications to get through. Texts from my Mom, for example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Push Notifications, the good, the bad, and the wtf could u not (UX Collective)</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00022/</guid>
      <description>Original post
Push notifications are incredibly handy for giving you important information. Your flight being delayed? Really helpful to know. Getting a notification for everything one of the Avengers is posting about? Probably not.
Just like you’re going to ignore or shut down the person who continuously interrupts you, you’re more likely to do the same to an app that bothers you with trivial information.
Push notifications are interruptive and we must be careful in our use of them if we are to retain our customers’ happiness and trust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving Your Product A Soul (Smashing Magazine)</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00008/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00008/</guid>
      <description>Original post
After a few years of designing products for clients, I began to feel fatigued. I wondered why. Turns out, I’d been chasing metric after metric. “Increase those page views!” “Help people spend more time in the app!” And it kept coming. Still, something was missing. I knew that meeting goals was part of what a designer does, but I could see how my work could easily become commoditized and less fulfilling unless something changed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving Your Product A Soul (Smashing Magazine)</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00009/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00009/</guid>
      <description>Original post
After a few years of designing products for clients, I began to feel fatigued. I wondered why. Turns out, I’d been chasing metric after metric. “Increase those page views!” “Help people spend more time in the app!” And it kept coming. Still, something was missing. I knew that meeting goals was part of what a designer does, but I could see how my work could easily become commoditized and less fulfilling unless something changed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One idea that could curb harassment on social media</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00020/</guid>
      <description>Original post
I have an idea about how to help people being harassed, and it’s about how people get and manage their replies.
This idea is more of an umbrella in a shitstorm. It’s a short-term solution that helps us stay dry while we try to get indoors to safety.
How we can filter replies # The core of this idea is that anyone could mention you, share or like your updates, but you don’t see every reply.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for perfect readability with a little help from The Big Lebowski</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00026/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00026/</guid>
      <description>Original post
I’ve had lots of conversations about typography over the last few years. Which is cool, because I love it so much (so much that I decided to make my own typeface). It’s exciting to see so many designers caring about making a beautiful group of letters that people want to read.
One common theme I see in these conversations is how to get the best readability with text. We usually end up talking about serif vs sans serif, line height, line spacing, and other tricks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Make An Effective Style Guide With Adobe Fireworks (Smashing Magazine)</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00011/</guid>
      <description>Original post
I started with style guides like any other obsessive-compulsive designer: with the desire to make it simple to maintain and grow a design. Plus, knowing which component to use in a given situation is nice, too, right? Since making this a regular practice, I’ve found it’s been like having a nice combination of a CSS class and a pattern library all in one.
One of the first questions, understandably, is why use Fireworks for a style guide?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iOS Grid System, A Free Extension For Adobe Fireworks (Smashing Magazine)</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00016/</guid>
      <description>Original post
About The Author # Joshua Mauldin is a design leader and visual artist who got his start creating websites for bands. Since then, he’s designed 5-star mobile apps and built … More about Joshua ↬
Email Newsletter # Your (smashing) email
Weekly tips on front-end &amp;amp; UX. Trusted by 200,000+ folks.
I’ll come right out and say it. I think the grid is the unsung hero of a good design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My real problem with in-app rating modules</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00017/</guid>
      <description>Original post
“Like this app? Give us 5 stars! UGH STOP PLZ.” # The conversation where folks are growing collectively tired of being asked to rate apps has been interesting to watch.
Some tech folks want to encourage users to rate an app 1 star because they asked for a rating. I think that’s unfair, because that doesn’t seem like a real review at all to me. It doesn’t tell me that the app is buggy, that it steals my data, or doesn’t alert me to a tornado.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How smartphones could improve texting emergency services</title>
      <link>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00010/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshuamauldin.com/docs/published-00010/</guid>
      <description>Original post
As of May 24, 2014, the main 4 carriers in the US will allow texting with 911. That’s great, but I wondered what it would look like if smartphones could build on top of that idea.
I want design to do good and feel like a moment of crisis is an ideal spot to employ thoughtful design to ease a difficult situation. Plus, it’s fun to weave different technologies together.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
